扛住. 看着点, 小心点.
Hold it. Watch it, watch it.
扛住, 扛住, 扛住了.
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
- 好了. 好了.
- 谢谢你.
- Got it. Got it.
- Thank you.
用肩扛,
把它扛在肩上.
On your shoulder,
put it on your shoulder.
- 小心看路.
- Watch the step.
慢点, 慢点.
Easy, easy.
如果你需要搬到那里,
就说一声.
lf you need some help down there,
say something.
- 小心点.
- 继续走.
- Watch it.
- Keep it coming.
- 别走太快了.
- 慢点来.
- Don't go too fast.
- Easy.
那样就对了, 继续走.
That's it, come on.
你踩到我脚了.
You hit me in the foot.
小心车.
Watch the car.
- 车就在这儿.
- 好咧.
- The car's right here.
- That's it.
你小心看路.
Watch where you step.
哦, 不是吧.
Oh, man.
纳提?
Rusty?
纳提姓什么?
What was Rusty's last name?
托马吉.
Tomasky.
是他带我进乐团.
做巡回乐队管理员.
He got me in with the band.
l'm a roadie.
你们来双峰镇
干嘛?
What were you doing
in Twin Peaks?
我们是来刀河这儿
演出的,
We were supposed to play a gig
in Knife River,
但一个轮胎爆了.
but a tire on the van crapped out.
然后你遇见了一个人.
Then you met someone.
对, 这家伙--
这家伙从林子里走出来,
Yeah, this guy--
This guy came out of the woods,
就像大脚怪，野人之类的,
like Bigfoot or something,
他穿这一套怪异的衣服.
and he's wearing a weird suit.
然后我们和他聊了一会
And we talked to him for a while
之后他说他那儿有酒,
唔, 问我们要不要来点.
and he said he had some brew,
you know, would we like some.
纳提就跟着他去了.
So Rusty went with him.
之后就再也没见过他了.
l didn't see him after that.
我们要通知
纳提的父母.
We'll need to get in touch
with Rusty's parents.
他恨他的父母.
He hated his parents.
他一直住在摩西湖他叔叔那儿
直到我们打算--
He's staying with his uncle
in Moses Lake until we were gonna--
打算离开.
We were gonna move.
我们原来还想着去洛杉几的.
We were gonna move to L.A.
安迪.
Andy.
我的脚! 看着点儿.
My foot! Watch it.
他又把一个兵卒干掉了, 哈里,
He's taken another pawn, Harry,
但他没有预告我们这一步.
but he didn't tell us his move.
云顿·厄尔
玩过界了.
Windom Earle's
playing off the board.
- 早啊, 露西.
- 早, 杜鲁门警长.
- Morning, Lucy.
- Morning, Sheriff Truman.
- 早, 露西.
- 库珀探员.
- Morning, Lucy.
- Agent Cooper.
警长,
豪克警官在你的办公室.
Deputy Hawk is in your office,
sheriff.
他和一个人在里面
这人我之前没见过的,
He's with somebody
l've never seen before,
他看起来真的很伤心,
豪克正请他吃早餐安慰他.
but he looks really sad,
so Hawk is feeding him breakfast.
安迪.
Andy.
什么事, 露西?
Yes, Lucy?
对于拯救我们的星球
你知道多少?
What do you know
about saving our planet?
我知道这里面有数不清的问题.
l know it's in a lot of trouble.
安迪, 通常
我都心存太多疑虑.
Andy, l'm taking fate
into my own hands.
但这次，我要
自己掌握命运.
Mostly because the suspense
is too much for me.
明天是父日. 父亲节.
Tomorrow is D-day. Dad Day.
24小时内,
我将会选择谁做我孩子的父亲.
ln 24 hours,
l will choose the father of my child.
安迪·布伦南警官
Deputy Andy Brennan
或者服装推销员
理查·揣眉.
or clothing salesman
Richard Tremayne.
这跟双峰小姐比赛
有什么关系?
What does that have to do
with the Miss Twin Peaks contest?
我是想,
父亲和钱.
l-- l mean, we could use
the money.
我们都能用的上.
We could also use a father.
所以我要准备一篇关于
拯救我们行星的演讲稿,
So l have to make a speech
about saving our planet,
这是个很棒的概念,
which is a great concept,
但我仍然一点
头绪都没有.
but l have no idea
how to go about it.
没有.
Yet.
我倒认为人们在珍珠湖
钓鱼的时候，必须停止
l do know that people have got to stop
sinking their beer cans in Pearl Lake
往湖里丢啤酒罐的行为.
when they're fishing.
啤酒罐.
Beer cans.
而泡沫塑料则是永不死身，只要你还活着
一天，它都不会被分解掉的.
And Styrofoam never dies
for as long as you live.
真的么?
lt doesn't?
- 兰迪, 欧蕊回来了没?
- 没, 先生.
- Randy, has Audrey returned?
- No, sir.
- 没有她消息吗?
- 没有, 先生.
- No messages from her?
- No, sir.
你能派个人上去
帮我拿袋子吗? 麻烦了.
Would you send someone up
for my bags, please?
没问题.
Certainly.
保险公司
给我寄了好多表格资料
The insurance companies
send me so many forms
如果我得了心脏病
好像能让他们振奋不已似的.
that l could get a heart attack
just lifting them.
你好的很.
You're fine.
至于你心里面想什么
倒是值得你去担心.
lt's what's in your heart
you should be worried about.
我知道你有理由
去怀疑我.
l know that l have given you
reason to doubt me.
但我现在唯一的兴趣
就是为大家做好事.
But l am only interested in doing
the right thing for everybody.
那就离艾琳远点.
Then stay away from Eileen.
我做不到.
l can't.
只要谎言还存在，我就办不到.
Not as long as the lie survives.
见鬼, 你是怎么了，本. 事情没那么简单.
Damn it, Ben. lt's not that simple.
我是相信你的.
l believe you.
我为你做好事的欲望
鼓掌欢呼.
l applaud your desire
to do the right thing.
但善良对于你来说--
简直就像一颗定时炸弹.
But goodness in you is--
lt's like a time bomb.
把好好的生活给毁了
这样做没什么善良可言.
There's nothing good
about ruined lives.
这个过程的确艰难
又令人困顿.
lt is a confusing
and difficult process.
但我必须继续下去.
But l must continue.
对不起了, 伟.
Sorry, Will.
失陪了.
Excuse me.
- 杰克, 进来吧.
- 嗨.
- Jack, come on in.
- Hi.
你认识伟·海沃德?
You know Will Hayward?
认识, 你好. 我见过你女儿.
她真可爱.
Yes, hello. l've met your daughter.
She's a lovely girl.
是啊, 我该回
办公室去了.
Yeah, should be getting back
to my office.
又见到你真好, 庄.
Nice to see you again, John.
本, 悠着点, 拜托了.
Ben, be careful, please.
我一直在找欧蕊.
l've been looking for Audrey.
她应该马上就到了.
She should be back any minute.
本, 我得走了.
Ben, l gotta go.
我们说话这当口上
他们已经在帮我的飞机加油了.
They're gassing up the jet
as we speak.
那, 既然你这么赶
就先走吧
Well, you can call her
when you get to wherever it is
你可以随时给她电话.
you are in such a hurry to get to.
我的一个朋友--
A friend of mine--
除了朋友, 他还是
我的合伙人. --他被谋杀了.
He was more than a friend, he was
a partner. --he's been murdered.
女生.
Female child.
母, 艾琳·海沃德.
Mother, Eileen Hayward.
女, 唐娜·玛丽.
Daughter, Donna Marie.
父...
Father...
唐娜? 唐娜, 你在哪儿?
Donna? Donna, where are you?
- 怎么了, 妈?
- 豪克警官打电话来找你.
- What is it, Mom?
- Deputy Hawk is on the phone.
我马上来.
l'll be right there.
他说是紧要事.
He says it's important.
- 荷恩小姐, 有几个消息给你的.
- 好极了.
- Ms. Horne, l have several messages.
- Great.
那个我帮你拿吧.
l'll take that for you.
好的. 谢谢.
Okay. Thanks.
欧蕊.
Audrey.
库珀探员有事，
想请你去警局见他.
Agent Cooper would like to see you
at the sheriff's station.
哦, 这, 我现在有好多事要做.
今天下午吧.
Oh, well, l have a lot of work to do.
Maybe this afternoon.
立刻要去. 急事.
Now. lt's important.
那好吧.
Okay.
你走了，那停止格斯伍计划怎么办?
But what about Stop Ghostwood?
我要怎样
才能留着你?
How am l supposed
to get ahold of you?
我需要更多时间.
l need more time.
一个勇士死了.
A brave man is dead.
他是我的朋友,
我必须回去接替他的事.
He's my friend,
and l have to take his place.
你不打算回来了, 是吧?
You aren't coming back, are you?
我诅咒那些雨林烦事
真该死.
Damn this rainforest business
anyway.
没有我，你也能应付过来的.
You can handle this without me.
我不知道.
我好怕，我好虚弱.
l don't know.
l'm afraid that l'm weak.
本·荷恩, 虚弱?
谁会信啊.
Ben Horne, weak?
l find that hard to believe.
为善良仁慈而奋斗, 嗯?
Strive for goodness, huh?
先说最艰难的事实.
Tell the hardest truth first.
尽力而为吧.
Just do the best you can.
那就是你所能做到的.
That's all you really can do.
嗯, 我很抱歉
欧蕊不在.
Well, l'm sorry
that Audrey wasn't here.
我想你帮我
转交个东西给她.
l want you to give her
something for me.
告诉她我--
Tell her l--
给她就好了, 你会照办吗?
Just give it to her, will you?
祝你好运.
Good luck.
去查查看这些符号
和收割时分表
See if any of these symbols
have to do with
或者古代历法
有没有联系.
harvest schedules
or ancient calendars.
找出任何相关的古怪术语.
Look for any curious nomenclature.
知道了, 长官.
Got it, chief.
好好干, 卡皮.
Good work, Cappy.
- 少校. 战况如何?
- 哈里.
- Major. How goes the battle?
- Harry.
- 库珀探员.
- 少校, 你看起来很疲倦.
- Agent Cooper.
- Major, you look bushed.
是啊, 我花了一晚上终于搞到了
蓝皮书项目的档案，仔细看了个遍
Well, l spent the night obtaining and
perusing the Project Blue Book files
我读完云顿·厄尔的相关资料后.
regarding Windom Earle.
我发现自己难以入眠.
l found it impossible to sleep after.
你收集到什么情报?
What have you gleaned?
厄尔曾是我们中
最棒最聪明的一个.
Earle was the best
and brightest among us.
但是，当我们的注意力
转移到外太空
But when our attention
turned from outer space
就是围绕着双峰镇
树林这一带区域,
to the wooded areas
surrounding Twin Peaks,
他就开始变得神不守舍.
he became destructively obsessive.
厄尔的行为表现的过分激动
而且经常鬼鬼祟祟的.
Earle acted in an overzealous
and secretive manner.
不听命令，私自行动,
最终以暴力告终了.
Possessive of his assignments,
finally violent.
他被开除出项目了.
He was removed from the project.
我是在档案馆找到这个的.
l found this in the project archives.
这些-- 这些邪恶的男巫,
他们被称作, 德帕族,
These-- These evil sorcerers,
dugpas, they're called,
邪恶令他们不断的培育出邪恶,
除此没别的了.
they cultivate evil for the sake of evil,
nothing else.
为了黑暗
他们以黑暗代表自己
They express themselves
in darkness for darkness
而不受任何动机影响.
without leavening motive.
现在, 这，这份对黑暗炽热又强烈的忠贞
允许他们进入一个秘密的地方
Now, this-- This ardent purity
allows them to access a secret place
一个能让他们培育邪恶的程序
将呈几何级增长的地方,
where the cultivation of evil proceeds
in exponential fashion,
在那里, 邪恶的能量
就可以得到大幅促进.
and with it, the furtherance
of evil's resulting power.
这块能量园是有形的
正因如此, 它是可以被找到, 并进入的
This place of power is tangible
and as such, it can be found, entered
或许能以某种形式
对其加以利用.
and perhaps utilized
in some fashion.
德帕族给它起了
很多名字,
The dugpas have many names
for it,
但其中最主要的名字是--
守夜门.
but chief among them is the--
ls the Black Lodge.
你们不信我, 是吧?
你们以为我疯了.
You don't believe me, do you?
You think l'm mad.
以为我工作过度了.
Overworked.
算了吧，滚开.
Go away.
先生们, 当云顿·厄尔
抵达双峰镇,
Gentlemen, when Windom Earle
arrived in Twin Peaks,
我还以为
他是为报复我.
l assumed
he had come for vengeance.
而来的.
For me.
但我失算了.
But l miscalculated.
他暗中将自己混入
我们所关爱的人当中.
He has insinuated himself
into the lives of people l care for.
然后又滥杀无辜.
He has murdered innocents.
目的就在于转移注意力
是我们疲于奔命应战.
He has engaged us in subterfuge
and red herring.
这样我就不会特别留意一条漏网之鱼了.
A fish l don't particularly care for.
但所有这些动作
都不过是幌子罢了.
But all of these acts
are merely camouflage.
这背后，原来他自始至终
想要的是:
He's been after something else
all along:
守夜门.
The Black Lodge.
伙计们, 我们必须找出,
这守夜门, 到底和那个什么关系.
Fellas, we need to find out what this,
the Black Lodge, has to do with that.
你真的相信
这之间有联系?
Do you really believe
there's a connection?
云顿·厄尔相信, 哈里.
Windom Earle does, Harry.
好了. 哈里, 我们一定要把这些
档案彻底看个遍.
All right. Harry, we're gonna go
through these files from top to bottom.
卡皮, 我要你把一切有关
德帕族的事都挖出来.
Cappy, l want you to dig up
everything you can about the dugpas.
少校,
我想你最好去睡一觉.
Major,
l think you'd better hit the sack.
我可以舒服地伸个懒腰了.
l could use a good stretch.
或许在林子里散散步
有助于我清醒头脑.
Perhaps a walk in the woods
to clear my mind.
好主意.
别忘了给林子里的鸟带点面包屑.
Good idea.
Don't forget the bread crumbs.
对.
Right.
哈里, 我们开始吧.
Harry, let's do it.
你知道吗, 里欧, 哥伦布
发现的唯一 一件事
You know, Leo, the only thing
that Columbus discovered
就是他所失去的.
was that he was lost.
库珀和他的同党们
还不够老道呢.
Cooper and the gang
haven't even left the snide yet.
我知道他们所不知的.
l know something they don't know.
我知道某些小戴尔
几乎不会怀疑的事.
l know something young Dale
merely suspects.
蓝皮书项目.
Project Blue Book.
小人物,
盲目乐观的田凫鸟.
Little men,
pewits loaded with optimism.
他们有的威慑力就那么一丁点了
这简直就是一种鼓励啊.
They were a deterrent so slight
it was practically encouragement.
不过有几个问题
我倒想问布里格斯少校.
Yet l would like to ask Major Briggs
a question or three.
把他那粒小光头好好打磨抛光
看着它如此闪闪发亮.
Polish up that bald nub of his
and see what shines.
里欧, 也许, 我们俩该出去冒冒险，
舒展一下筋骨了.
Perhaps, Leo, we too
should venture out for a good stretch.
和少校重聚蓝皮书项目
那不很有趣嘛?
Wouldn't it be fun to have
a Project Blue Book reunion?
酒, 芝士, 畅谈旧时,
Wine, cheese, talk about old times,
再次换来过去那风花雪月
充满奇闻轶事的欢乐时光.
trade hilarious anecdotes
of the good old days.
我在想我生命中的碎石瓦砾
能为布里格斯的人生增添点风味.
l wonder what amongst my detritus
l can use to spice up Briggs' life.
里欧, 别傻站着了.
Leo, stop dawdling.
如果你这样站在外面,就麻烦了
鸽子会来戳你的.
lf you were outside,
you'd have trouble with pigeons.
"那是我们拯救那些树木的
唯一办法.
''And that's the only way
we're ever going to save the trees.
是时候要为我们的环境
积极行动起来了.
lt's time to stand up and kick some butt
for our environment.
在它为时已晚之前，为了我们大家."
Before it's too late for all of us.''
写的真美, 一字不差.
lt's beautiful, letter-perfect.
我不知道用
"积极行动"好不好.
l don't know about
the ''kick butt'' part.
改用"战斗"怎样?
How about ''fight''?
是时候要站起来
为我们的环境而战斗了.
lt's time to stand up
and fight for our environment.
这个词好多了.
Much better.
雪莉, 我一直在想.
Shelly, l've been thinking.
噢, 波比, 我懂, 我懂, 我懂.
Oh, Bobby, l know, l know, l know.
- 演讲算双--
- 别提什么比赛了.
- The speech counts double--
- Forget about the contest.
我一直在想关于我们的事.
l've been thinking about us.
你有吗?
You have?
我知道最近一直没有
给你太多关心.
l know that l have not been paying
the right kind of attention to you lately.
我忙着跟荷恩先生混.
l got busy with Mr. Horne.
我开始穿起套装, 好了,
然后我突然觉得走路也神气活现
l started wearing suits, okay,
and suddenly l'm walking around
趾高气扬起来了，好像我比
谁都重要.
like l'm more important
than everybody else.
你之前的确一副穷酸相.
You were pretty crummy.
波比, 我想你了.
Bobby, l've missed you.
我怀念我们在一起
做过的所有事.
l've missed all the things
we used to do together.
当我看见你亲那个
家伙时...脑袋就炸轰了.
When l saw you kissing
that guy...something snapped.
我当时几乎快气晕过去了,
lt was like my brain rolled over,
我这才看到原来这一切
对我有多么特别.
and l could see all the stuff
that was special to me.
这一切是如此重要.
All the stuff that matters.
我爱你, 雪莉.
l love you, Shelly.
我想以后都能
那样过.
And l wanna spend my time
with that.
我是说, 你知道么,
如果你可以的话,
l mean, you know,
if that's okay with you,
我愿意这样做, 你懂吗...
l'd like to do that, you know...
波比, 你觉得呢?
Bobby, what do you think?
幸运.
Lucky.
我真幸运.
Lucky me.
雪莉, 电话.
Shelly, telephone.
库珀探员的电话.
他有事找你.
Agent Cooper's on the line.
He needs to talk to you.
快点, 雪莉, 他说是要事.
Now, Shelly, he says it's important.
- 我有天大的好消息.
- 是什么?
- l've got great news.
- What?
是诺玛·詹宁斯
和理查·揣眉将会加入评委组.
lt's going to be Norma Jennings
and Richard Tremayne.
揣眉是第三位评委.
这次十拿九稳了.
Tremayne is the third judge.
lt's in the bag.
那, 现在, 我必须要确保.
Well, now, l have to be sure.
宝贝, 我必须确保
我会赢.
Baby, l have to be sure
l'm gonna win.
哦, 我的上帝, 这家伙是英国人
或者是巴哈马人什么的.
Oh, my God, this guy's British
or Bahamian or something.
他会为你的魅力而拜倒.
He's bound to fall for your charms.
我们会想个办法
把你们俩弄到一块, 单独.
We'll find some way
to get you two together, alone.
然后呢,
你故意穿一件有裂缝的衣服.
And then,
you put on a dress with a slit.
哦, 那条大裂缝一直
裂到西雅图那儿去.
Oh, the slit cut halfway
up to Seattle.
在之后呢, 渐渐偎依过去
And then, nestle in real close to him
当他一眼看到
这双美腿
and when he gets a look
at those gams
和闻到洒在你身上的
法国香水，那他...
and smells that French perfume
dripping off you and then...
...就会开始
迷失在这双棕色眼睛里了...
...becomes lost
in those brown eyes...
噢, 好了. 好了.
Oh, stop it. Stop it.
停下, 你这小母狐, 你.
Stop it, you vixen, you.
我快受不了.
l can't stand it anymore.
为什么我们不干脆私奔算了...
Why can't we just elope and...
不. 现在不行, 直到我赢了为止, 亲爱的.
No. Now, not until l've won, darling.
那时，只有到那时,
我才会嫁给你.
Then, and only then,
l will marry you.
噢, 你好苛刻哦, 亲爱的.
Oh, you're so strict, darling.
我真是个遭罪市长啊.
And l am the blasted mayor.
哦, 乖, 宝贝, 来这里.
Oh, now, baby, come here.
好了.
lt's okay.
你们每个人
都以古怪的方式.
Each of you received
a piece of this poem.
收到一片诗,
还连带着这个邀请.
Each in a curious manner,
along with this invitation.
我们都去了公路吧,
但没有人出现.
We all went to the Roadhouse,
nobody showed up.
你们最近有接触过
一个陌生人吗?
Have any of you had contact recently
with a stranger?
有没有留下什么印象，比如神经兮兮的,
风度优雅，又或是有的莫名其妙的?
Someone who struck you as peculiar,
personable or just plain puzzling?
嗯, 见过一个生人
他说是我爸爸的一个朋友.
Well, there was this strange guy who
said he was a friend of my father's.
我收到诗那天,
还收到10美金小费，就放在咖啡杯旁.
Same day l got the poem,
l got a $1 0 tip for a cup of coffee.
那很不常见.
That's unusual.
告诉你, 我有次在图书馆里碰见了
一个风趣的老头儿.
You know, there was a funny old guy
at the library.
他要我
为他念这首诗.
He asked me
to read the poem to him.
3个都有.
All three.
雪莉, 靠近点仔细看.
Shelly, take a closer look.
你觉得这笔迹
眼熟吗?
Does this handwriting
look familiar to you?
是里欧的.
lt's Leo's.
听清楚了.
Listen carefully.
我要你们每个人
每天来警察局报告2次.
l want each of you to check in
with the sheriff twice a day.
早上9点,
晚上9点各一次.
Nine o'clock in the morning,
9:00 at night.
我要你们的父母
全天候知道你们的所在地.
l want your parents
to know your whereabouts at all times.
不管你走路上学,
还是开车去上班,
You walk to school,
you drive to work,
都确保你们
不要独自一人.
make sure
that you do not do so alone.
请相信我
当我告诉你们要小心时.
Please believe me
when l tell you to be very careful.
你们的情形很危险.
You're in danger.
我们都是.
We all are.
你会欣赏
德帕族的, 里欧.
You would've appreciated
the dugpas, Leo.
远古男巫对邪恶的忠贞不二.
Ancient sorcerers bent on evil.
颇像印度教朝拜者对
暴虐黑暗女神迦梨的朝圣.
Rather like the Kali worshippers
in lndia.
我可以告诉你,
又是一帮出色的小丑.
Another fine bunch of zanies,
l can tell you.
一日三餐, 以血为生.
Blood for breakfast, blood for lunch.
那都是好时光啊.
Those were the good old days.
- 雪莉.
- 很好啊, 里欧, 你还记得.
- Shelly.
- Very good, Leo, you remember.
浅薄庸俗的小娼妇.
Tawdry little trollop.
雪莉.
Shelly.
这事我只和你说好了, 小老弟,
Just between you and me, old boy,
你妻子对婚姻的忠诚度
有相当摩登的看法.
your wife has some
fairly modern views on marital fidelity.
但这不要紧.
But no matter.
她仍然适合做皇后.
She is still fit for a queen.
你会哀悼她的死吗, 里欧?
我很怀疑哦.
Would you mourn her passing, Leo?
l doubt it.
她的死, 里欧.
Her death, Leo.
雪莉即将迎来超度.
Shelly's imminent demise.
会非常简单, 真的.
lt's very simple, really.
雪莉在双峰小姐中胜出,
然后死去.
Shelly wins Miss Twin Peaks,
Shelly dies.
也许你愿意帮一把.
Maybe you'd like to help.
雪莉. 不要.
Shelly. No.
好家伙, 你手上拿的什么东西?
Good God, what have you got there?
别, 里欧, 我求你了.
No, Leo, l'm begging you.
- 求求你. 饶了我吧, 里欧.
- 爱雪莉.
- l prithee. Have mercy, Leo.
- Love Shelly.
可怜的里欧.
Poor Leo.
或多或少, 我们都会对傻子有点好感.
We are all love's fools, more or less.
但你会吸取教训的, 正如,
But you will learn, as l have,
憎恨对我的价值.
the value of hate.
嗨.
Hi.
- 嗨, 爸爸.
- 哦, 欧蕊.
- Hi, Daddy.
- Oh, Audrey.
- 欢迎到家, 小蜜糖.
- 谢谢.
- Welcome home, honey.
- Thanks.
我今早就回来了
但库珀探员有事找我, 所以就...
l got back this morning but
Agent Cooper needed to see me, so...
出什么事了吗?
Something's wrong?
有个变态给我送了一首诗.
Some creep sent me a poem.
我打电话去杰克房间,
但他不在那儿.
l tried to call Jack's room,
but he wasn't there.
- 你知道他去哪儿了?
- 欧蕊, 你不在的时候,
- Do you know where he is?
- Audrey, while you were gone,
- 我突发奇想，有了一个极不可思议的点子.
- 是什么?
- l had the most incredible brainstorm.
- What?
停止格斯伍的活动
需要一个代言人.
The Stop Ghostwood movement
needs a spokesperson.
一个能见度高的形象
Someone with a highly visible profile
能激励我们的社团
并肩作战的形象.
to be able to inspire
our community to action.
爸爸, 杰克在哪儿?
Daddy, where's Jack?
这你能做到, 欧蕊.
You can do it, Audrey.
作为双峰小姐出现,
As Miss Twin Peaks,
你就能借此公众平台
成为那个代言人了
you could be that spokesperson
and you could use your public platform
- 不, 爸.
- 作为一个辩论环境问题的论坛.
- No, Dad.
- as a forum for environmental debate.
欧蕊, 听我说, 你能做到的.
Audrey, listen, you can do it.
只有你能把我们的信息
带给人们.
Only you can take our message
to the people.
爸爸,
庄·爵斯廷·维乐在哪儿?
Daddy,
where is John Justice Wheeler?
- 他走了.
- 他要去哪儿?
- He's gone.
- Where did he go?
巴西发生惨剧了
要他立即回去处理.
Some tragedy in Brazil
demanded his immediate attention.
他给你留了一封信,
在我这儿呢.
He left a letter for you,
l have it here.
爸爸.
Daddy.
- 他什么时候走的?
- 几分钟之前出发去机场了.
- When did he leave?
- A few minutes ago to the airport.
欧蕊,
那双峰小姐的事呢?
Audrey,
what about Miss Twin Peaks?
我迟点再和你商量这事儿,
好么? 我保证.
l'll talk with you about this later,
okay? l promise.
欧蕊. 欧蕊. 欧蕊?
Audrey. Audrey. Audrey?
乔西, 我看见你的脸了.
Josie, l see your face.
- 兰迪.
- 在.
- Randy.
- Yes.
哦, 算了. 你.
Oh, forget it. You.
你有车吗?
Do you have a car?
一辆货车. 开起来顺极了.
A truck. Runs like a dream.
那太好了, 我们走.
Great, let's go.
等等. 噢, 抱歉.
Wait. Oh, l'm sorry.
快点. 快点.
Come on. Come on.
这, 符号表示时间.
Well, the symbols suggest a time.
似乎很明确.
Seems clear.
- 什么时间?
- 我不知道.
- A time for what?
- l don't know.
刚开始我还以为是一个路标.
也可能是个邀请信号.
At first l thought it was a signpost.
Perhaps it's an invitation.
又或者2者皆是.
Or both.
少校在哪儿?
Where's the major?
他现在应该到了吧.
He should be here by now.
安迪, 给布里格斯太太打个电话,
看少校是否还在家里.
Andy, give Mrs. Briggs a call,
see if the major's home yet.
在干嘛呢, 库?
What is it, Coop?
哦, 在想
安妮·伯本.
Oh, just thinking
about Annie Blackburn.
呀, 乖乖,
我还不知道你也会走神.
Well, bless your heart,
l've never known your mind to wander.
噢, 哈里,
我已经走神一整天了.
Oh, Harry,
l've been feeling this way all day.
你知道么, 我如常工作,
我头脑清晰而专注
You know, l proceed as usual,
my mind clear and focused
但突然间, 也不知从哪里冒出来的,
我就看到她的脸和听到她的声音了.
and suddenly, out of nowhere,
l see her face and l hear her voice.
很自然的, 我要努力调整自己,
重新回到手头上的任务,
Naturally, l try to reorient myself,
come back to the task at hand,
但那些影像仍逗留在脑海里.
but the image remains.
有时我确实觉得很晕眩.
Sometimes l actually feel dizzy.
恋爱中的人
都那样.
A man in love
is supposed to feel that way.
那, 我的症状通常是
得疟疾.
Well, my symptoms suggest
the onset of malaria.
但我的一生中没有比这感觉更好的了.
But l've never felt better in my life.
抱歉, 哈里, 这听起来太傻了.
l'm sorry, Harry, that sounds foolish.
不, 没有的事, 伙计, 这是幸运才对.
No, no, man, it sounds lucky.
家, 家在此山中
Home, home on the range
鹿在哪里?
羚羊在玩乐
Where the deer
And the antelope play
那里难得听到
令人沮丧的话语
Where seldom is heard
A discouraging word
你好啊, 伟伯.
Hello, Wilbur.
天空永远是万里无云
And the skies are not cloudy all day
好久不见了, 小布里.
Long time no see, Briggsy.
里欧.
Leo.
看来，终于
有人给你作伴了.
lt looks like
you've finally found your calling.
去参加没什么坏处啊.
Couldn't hurt to give it a shot.
也许明年吧.
Maybe next year.
安妮, 全世界在外面.
勇敢点，加入吧.
Annie, there's a whole world out there.
Jump in.
"一不做.
二不休."
''Hear the other side.
See the other side.''
圣·奥古斯汀说的.
St. Augustine.
- 咖啡?
- 没错.
- Coffee?
- You bet.
- 你有心事.
- 是的.
- Something's troubling you.
- Yes.
原意聊聊吗?
Would you like to talk about it?
安妮, 我陷入了一宗
相当复杂的调查
Annie, l'm involved
in a fairly complicated investigation
要求我要高度集中精神.
requiring my complete attention.
然而我却花了大部分时间
在想你.
Yet l spend most of my time
thinking of you.
我知道那滋味.
l know the feeling.
我今天整个上午
在煎蛋上看到的，都是你的脸.
l've been seeing your face
in fried eggs all this morning.
你知道么, 有人相信科学研究上说
吸引力是化学反应.
You know, there are those who believe
in a scientific basis for attraction.
的一种主要成分.
lt's chemical.
就这样吗?
ls that what it is?
我不知道.
l don't know.
很难理解的
透彻.
Hard to comprehend
without perspective.
就是.
Yeah.
我花了5年
试图去理解它.
l spent five years
trying to comprehend it.
嘿.
Hey.
对我来说真的很难.
lt's hard for me.
但我对你有信心,
就我们而言, 我能明白它.
But l have faith in you,
in us, because l understand it.
我们非常相似.
We're very much alike.
这有帮助.
lt helps.
我们想太多了.
We think too much.
"我们所观察的
并不是大自然本身,
''What we observe
is not nature itself,
而是大自然向我们
暴露出质疑的方法."
but nature exposed
to our method of questioning.''
海森堡说的.
Heisenberg.
不如我们去打保龄球吧.
Maybe we should go bowling.
跳舞如何?
How about dancing?
我不会.
l don't know how.
我教你. 很简单的.
l'll teach you. lt's easy.
- 几时?
- 今晚.
- When?
- Tonight.
他在那里, 加大油门.
There he is, step on it.
杰克! 杰克, 停下!
Jack! Jack, stop!
我原来猜想连一句再见
都说不上了.
l guess a simple goodbye
was out of the question.
我爱你.
l love you.
我也爱你.
l love you too.
- 你一定要走吗?
- 是的.
- Do you have to leave?
- Yes.
那你什么时候会回来?
When will you be back?
我不知道.
l don't know.
我还是个处女.
l'm a virgin.
什么?
What?
我要你和我做爱.
l want you to make love with me.
什么? 此时此地?
What? Here and now?
你不有飞机嘛?
lt's your jet.
那真得感谢上帝了.
Thank God for that.
你第一次在猫头鹰山洞
看到那些符号是几时的事?
When did you first see
the symbol in Owl Cave?
我是不能随意
泄露那些信息的.
l'm not at liberty
to divulge that information.
骗子.
Cheater.
那些洞穴画到底有什么意思?
What does the cave painting mean?
我是不能随意
泄露那些信息的.
l'm not at liberty
to divulge that information.
真见鬼, 我就是喜欢有军事头脑的人.
Damn, but l love the military mind.
北卡罗莱纳州
的首都叫什么?
What is the capital
of North Carolina?
罗利城.
Raleigh.
这对我一点好处都没有.
Fat lot of good that will do me.
少校, 我钦佩您的刚毅.
Major, l admire your fortitude.
如果我有时间和耐性的话,
Had l had the time and patience,
我们会将这个游戏
无了期的玩下去.
we might continue this game
indefinitely.
然而...
However...
...我两者都没有.
...l have neither.
接着咯.
Catch.
你的名字? 劳驾了.
Your name, please?
加兰·布里格斯.
Garland Briggs.
加兰, 在这世上
你最害怕什么?
Garland, what do you fear most
in the world?
很有可能是
爱不够.
The possibility
that love is not enough.
哦, 加兰, 行行好吧, 我都快哭了.
Oh, Garland, please, l shall weep.
你妻子体重多少?
How much does your wife weigh?
115磅.
One hundred and fifteen pounds.
噢, 不错嘛.
Oh, good for her.
现在, 你第一次在猫头鹰山洞
看到那幅岩石雕刻是几时的事?
Now, when did you first see
the petroglyph in Owl Cave?
在-- 在梦里.
ln-- ln dreams.
什么样的梦?
What kind of dreams?
我那晚正和库珀探员
在钓鱼.
l was night fishing
with Agent Cooper.
有一束关,
从远处射来.
There was a light,
guardian beyond it.
我被掳走了, 但我记得...
l was taken, but my mind...
我还认得那些符号.
Still l recognized the signs.
那些符号是什么意思?
What do the signs mean?
某一天,
当木星和土星相遇时,
There's a time,
if Jupiter and Saturn meet,
他们就会来接你.
they will receive you.
加兰, 加兰.
Garland, Garland.
加兰, 加兰, 我原想着
这会是一次漫长的对话呢.
Garland, Garland, l was hoping
for a lengthy conversation.
里欧, 扶少校上床.
Leo, put the major to bed.
恐怕他的脑袋
已经开始迷糊了.
l'm afraid his mind
has begun to wander.
某一天,
如果木星和土星相遇时.
There's a time,
if Jupiter and Saturn meet.
他的女仆人, 琼斯,
His woman servant, Jones,
在他死后不久
就把这个送来给我了.
delivered this to me
shortly after he died.
埃卡最后的遗物.
Eckhardt's last bequest.
一个聪明的玩笑, 也许吧,
又或是些有价值的东西.
A clever jape, perhaps,
or something of value.
试试这样.
Try this.
不, 你看, 每一个盒子
都有打开的秘诀.
No, you see, there's a secret
to opening each of these boxes.
而这个
快让我抓狂了.
And this one
is about to drive me mad.
啊呀, 安德鲁,
给我说点好听的吧.
Oh, Andrew,
tell me something good.
我们从巴黎到北京的外国投资者
已经在磨拳擦掌，都等得不耐烦了.
Our foreign investors are chomping
at the bit from Paris to Beijing.
你很快就会拥有自己的高尔夫球场了.
You're going to get your golf course.
就建在大北方酒店
的旁边.
Right next to
The Great Northern Hotel.
那本杰明会尽一切所能
来阻止我们的.
And Benjamin is doing everything
he can to stop us.
那, 为时已晚了. 他当时还在运作
这个项目的时候,
Well, it's too late. When the project
was still in his possession,
就已经把一切可能的障碍都给清除了:
Ben cleared every possible hurdle:
分区, 环境影响报告书.
The zoning, the impact statements.
他就是他自己
最大的敌人.
He was and is
his own worst enemy.
一向如此. 你在干嘛?
As always. What are you doing?
没干嘛, 凯萨琳, 只不过试试
几个简单的组合.
Nothing, Catherine, l'm just trying
a few simple combinations.
- 我来, 我来.
- 别闹, 凯萨琳.
- Let me, let me.
- No, Catherine.
埃卡的生日.
Eckhardt's birthday.
我的生日.
My birthday.
这礼物到达那天的日期.
The day the gift arrived.
把它给我.
Give it to me.
- 哦, 真无聊.
- 我打开的.
- Oh, what a bore.
- l opened it.
安德鲁...
Andrew...
这个，我完全没有任何心理准备.
l'm not completely prepared for this.
就想着这是相拥着在散步就行了,
行吗?
Just think of it as a walking embrace,
all right?
2个人步调
一致.
Two people stepping
as one would step.
- 目前为止, 感觉还行.
- 现在, 跟着我就行了.
- So far, so good.
- Now, just follow me.
我们互相跟步.
We'll follow each other.
好.
Good.
一些残留的记忆.
lt's genetic memory.
以前见过爸妈跳林迪舞.
Mom and Dad danced the lindy.
你掌握了.
You've got it.
你身体靠着我的感觉真好.
Your body feels nice against mine.
我也觉得是.
l was just thinking the same thing.
听着, 我是否太急进了点--
Listen, if l'm being too forward--
- 除了你的吻，我还想要更多.
- 例如?
- l want more than your kisses.
- For instance?
- 我要--
- 这东西开了?
- l want--
- This thing on?
欢迎光临今晚的
选美节决赛
Welcome to this final night
of festivities
庆祝双峰小姐...
celebrating the Miss Twin Peaks...
正如你们--
这该死的, 这鬼东西到底开了没有?
As some of you--
Damnation, is this damn thing on?
我的意思是
我明白你为何犹豫不决了,
What l mean is
l understand why you hesitate,
那么无微不至的关怀我.
why you treat me with care.
除了派生出
圣经章节和祈祷者,
The convent evokes the image
of helpless women,
修道院还唤起了我
fearful of the thought of any emotion
对无依无靠女人们的影像，
对所有感情都产生恐惧.
other than those derived
from scripture and prayer.
但当你抱着我,
But when you hold me,
当我们接吻,
when we kiss,
我感到安全和充满了渴望.
l feel safe and eager.
我一点都害怕了
l'm not afraid
你令我产生了
所有感觉和冲动.
of anything
that you make me feel or want.
这开了吗? 这开了吗?
ls this on? ls this on?
我开始有点烦他
这样搅和了.
l'm beginning to tire
of his interruptions.
- 欢迎来到...
- 我不知道. 我觉得他挺可爱的.
- Welcome to...
- l don't know. l think he's cute.
- ...今晚的决赛晚会...
- 你觉得可爱?
- ...this final night of festivities...
- You do?
我想或许
我还是会参赛的.
l think that maybe
l will enter after all.
- 双峰小姐选美比赛?
- 何妨呢?
- The Miss Twin Peaks contest?
- Why not?
"一不做.
二不休."
''Hear the other side.
See the other side.''
还有什么比参加双峰小姐
更合适去开始新生活的地方吗.
There's worse places to start
than Miss Twin Peaks.
这简直就像是一个童话故事.
lt's like a fairy tale.
你就是女王.
And you're the queen.
别.
No.
真是活受罪.
What a gyp.
终于遇到了你的梦中情人,
Finally meet the man of my dreams,
而下一刻, 没想到吧，
他却已经上了巴西的飞机.
next thing l know,
he's on a plane to Brazil.
终有一天他会回来的.
He'll be back one day.
- 他答应过的.
- 是啊.
- He promised.
- Yeah.
嗯, 他还答应过带我去钓鱼
而我们始终没去成.
Well, he also promised
to take me fishing and we never did.
爱真让人讨厌.
Love stinks.
- 钓鱼?
- 是啊.
- Fishing?
- Yeah.
去珍珠湖之类的.
Pearl Lake or something.
我倒是有些钓鱼工具在货车上.
l have some tackle in the truck.
你有吗?
You do?
欧蕊, 治疗伤心的方法
有很多,
Audrey, there are many cures
for a broken heart,
但却没有多少机会能见到
鳟鱼在月光下跃龙门哦.
but nothing quite like
a trout's leap in the moonlight.
钓鱼去?
May l?
那好吧.
You may.
木星和土星相遇
Jupiter and Saturn meet
噢, 干麦大丰收
Oh, what a crop of mummy wheat
我们的语无伦次少校所说的行星
不单只是远程天体.
The planets our babbling major
spoke of are more than distant orbs.
他们是, 其实, 是一个锺.
They are, in fact, a clock.
一个会报时的锺.
A clock that tells the time.
而时间...
And the time...
随着滴答声
越拉越近.
Time draws nearer
with each ticking tock.
戴尔说的没错. 那幅洞穴壁画
是一张加入族群的请柬,
Dale wasn't far wrong. The cave
painting is an invitation of sorts,
告知我们何时开始狂欢.
telling us when the revels begin.
但戴尔不知道
在哪里可以找到它.
But what Dale doesn't know
is where to find it.
因此, 你看, 这洞穴壁画
不仅是一张请柬,
For, you see, the cave painting
is not only an invitation,
它还是一张地图.
it is also a map.
一张通往守夜门的地图!
A map to the Black Lodge!
这里有些不对劲.
There's something wrong.
这不对.
这儿肯定有点不对劲.
This isn't right.
There's something wrong here.